welcome to meditating which Arbor Bakey
I'm a cognitive psychologist and a
cognitive scientist at the University of
Toronto academically teach and
scientifically study mindfulness and
related phenomena like Insight flow
mystical experience transformative
experience higher states of
consciousness cultivation of wisdom and
the aspiration to enlightenment I have
been practicing the pasta meditation
meta contemplation Tai Chi Chuan and
chicom for over 29 years and teaching
them professionally for close to 20
years welcome if you're joining us for
the first time please know that this is
a progressive course the introductory
course is done and we're now teaching an
advanced technique that builds on the
previous instruction every other Monday
we meet Monday through Friday and we sit
every day and there's Q&A at the end
please keep the Q&A at the end of these
sessions two questions concerning this
new ecology practices course more
encompassing questions please come to my
live stream on YouTube general Q&A every
third Friday at 3 p.m. yes
Eastern Time and I believe that's June
19th of this month for those of you who
are just joining and want to catch up I
would recommend look for links in the
district in the description of this
video to previous videos do the first
lesson join us every day Monday through
Friday and then try to watch one of the
previous lessons a new one each Saturday
or Sunday so that you'll eventually be
able to to catch up with us
I believe that's everything we need to
go over right now or one more thing
please if you could like this video
stream that will help to raise its
profile in the search algorithm and help
me to help more people so thank you very
much for that all right so that's your
basic posture ready I say your phones on
do not disturb and then we will begin
together when I say begin begin
slowly began to come out of your
practice trying as best you can to
integrate with your cultivated in your
practice if your everyday consciousness
and cognition
perhaps by reciting the five promises to
yourself
here we have time for a couple questions
one from Ronnie Chan they were doing a
group Lexi o Divino which turned out to
be very powerful and wondered afterwards
should we express our business with the
things others say during or after
practice or at all you should express
your residents in your appreciation what
other people are saying at some point as
it develops more clear I've started on a
workshop on this I want to explain the
process of how you take Alexia Divina
into the logos but an answer to your
specific question money chan uh yes you
should do that but when you are
resonating stated from your perspective
don't say this is what you're doing say
this is what's coming alive for me this
is what's resonating for me and what
you're saying it's very important that
we do that you might also want to note
how you're not only resonating with what
other people are saying and this is a
little bit more subtle but precisely
therefore more profound how you're all
resonating with something together this
is the logos the word
that's coming through and let's see if
you know how all of your gap being
gathered together
that's what logos originally meant so
dear logos dialog so that you come to
belong together that's what you're
experiencing the residence what's that
overall resonance not just
person-to-person but every one to the
gestalt to the whole anyways I'm very
glad to hear that the lexical group
Luxio is very powerful for you
so we typically have to have a very hard
out on Thursday was on Tuesdays I
encourage you all to keep up the ecology
practices we're all moving through it at
different paces but one of the deep
lessons I've learned from how I was
taught
it's that it's the ecology as a whole
and the way it takes on a life of its
all that that is what gives us
self-correcting self-transcending
self-righting path that we can walk upon
in good faith with the path with
ourselves when we thought with each
other
buddhadharma sign there please thank you
for joining I want to thank my good
friend and techno major Omar was always
there and my beloved son Jason behind
the scenes pinch-hitting when necessary
please subscribe the channel to be
notified of the next video on the
subscription on my home page you'll find
links to a lecture series awakening from
the meaning crisis links to a discussion
series a hold dialogo series voices with
ricky where these ideas are developed
and deepened and extended into an entire
way of life and perhaps a new culture a
new worldview and by others who might
benefit by sharing this series trying to
help as many people in these very
chaotic and confusing times to increase
the resiliency they're out there add
activity the discernment their ability
to see through and illusion
into what's real and to what really
matters please join the discord server
their link is in the description Brett
is here pleasure of doubt always discord
server they have people there doing this
set meeting afterwards doing some group
Alexio sometimes I believe in discussion
I'm there every second Monday at 6 p.m.
Eastern time doing Q&A many of the
people that
our own voices with Rebecca showing up
regularly or QA Paul Vander clay godsend
stocked gray gun reeks I know that
Jordan Hall is going to come on etc so
just that's a very powerful and
nourishing resource we do this every
weekday morning at 9:30 Eastern Time
please remember the continuity of
practice is more important than quantity
of practice there's no enemy worse than
your own mind and body no Fred no Ally
no truth companion on the path greater
than your own mind and body be laps unto
yourselves I'll see you all tomorrow
take good care